NZUBECHUKWU NWANORUE

111 Findon Way, Skelmersdale WN8 6HG Tel: 07503592348 •Email: nnwanorue@gmail.com

PROFILE

Petroleum and Gas engineering graduate with broad-ranging industrial skills, able to work both independently and as a supportive team member. Experience in petroleum production, gas flow and distribution and environmental sustainability. Able to quickly learn new things and assimilate information, summarize and draw conclusions. Confident presenting to both technical and less-skilled audiences. Thrives on new intellectual challenges.

RELEVANT SKILLS

Communication – Excellent oral and written communication skills

- Presenting Hydrogen Economy research results to stakeholders (up to 300 people)
- Preparing Masters thesis (20,000 words) on challenges of carbon storage in geological formations
- Presenting technical papers at Society of Petroleum Engineers (SPE) conferences
- Teaching and demonstrating at undergraduate practical and tutorial sessions (2011-2016)

Analytical and Problem-solving Ability

• Proactive approach to problem solving and possesses an ability to pay attention to detail

Customer Focus

Experienced in placing customer first, empathizing and active listening

Teamwork

- A wealth of experience in teamwork gained from previous job roles and extracurricular activities.
- Collaborating with a team to deliver projects and test research results

IT Skills

 Proficient use of Microsoft Excel, Word and PowerPoint. Basic knowledge of JAVA, Python, and C++. Use of industrial software like Eclipse, Promax, Petrel.

Leadership

 Experienced team leader having held previous leadership positions and understand how to motivate a team.

Learnability– Accepting to unlearn and relearn knowledge wherever necessary.

WORK EXPERIENCE

General Machine Operator, PEPSICO UK

(October 2021- Present)

Responsibilities:

- Start up, shut down and operation of equipment
- Co-ordination of other team members in the area
- Sanitation on the line.
- Quality control with ownership of compliance checks and paperwork
- Seasoning interactions.
- Housekeeping duties to ensure health and safety and hygiene is maintained

Safety Steward, Manchester United Football Club

(January 2020 – September 2021)

• To be responsible for the safety and comfort of spectators within a designated area at all times.

Warehouse Operative Team Leader, Hermes Warrington

(July 2020 – October 2021)

- Coordinating and directing the activities of the Manual Department
- Reporting to the Supervisor and Manger on hourly target rates
- Using company electronic device to unload inbound trailers

Laboratory Assistant, Petroleum Training Institute, Nigeria

(April 2017 – May 2018)

- Assisting generally with drilling fluid sample analysis from offshore drilling
- Participated in short courses that granted me better orientation in current oil and gas practices in the global industry

Sales Assistant, Next Door Pharmacy Limited, Nigeria

(*January* 2016 – *February* 2017)

- Be involved in stock control and management
- Assisting and answering customer queries
- Reporting to sales manager

University Placement, National Oil Spill Detection and Response Agency (NOSDRA)

(June 2015 – December 2015)

- Participated in Joint Investigation Visits to Oil Spill Zones
- Participated in Clean-Up Inspections in Oil Spill Zones

EDUCATION

MSc, University of Salford Petroleum and Gas Engineering – Distinction

2019 - 2020

- Project to investigate the challenges of carbon storage in geological formation
- Project to design a gas distribution network, delivering a capacity of gas through a given distance
- University of Salford petroleum and gas scholar award

B.Eng, Federal University of Technology Petroleum Engineering – 2.2

2011-2016

- Modules: Engineering thermodynamics, Engineering drawing, Strength of material, Engineering mathematics, Petroleum geology, Drilling technology, Reservoir engineering, Applied geophysics in petroleum exploration
- Awarded Agbami Medical and Engineering professional scholarship

Alvana Model Secondary School

2008-2011

O- Level, West African Senior School Certificate

CERTIFICATIONS

Health and Safety LVL 2 Certificate

(February 2020)

Action Counters Terrorism (ACT) Certificate

(February 2020)

HSE Levels I-III (Award in Health and Safety at work; Risk Assessment Practical application; Award in Environmental Awareness)- (March 2018)

INTERESTS

Reading, Football, Music, Volunteering, Nature and Environment are my leisure activities, combined they have taught me self-discipline, working well with others and attention to detail.

References are available upon request